Guide to the Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain Papers M1835
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain papers
1898-1975
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Comhaire-Sylvain, Suzanne
M1835
9 Linear Feet (17 manuscript boxes, 3 flat boxes)
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Separated Materials
Glass recordings have been transferred to the Archives of Recorded Sound, located in the Music Building on the Stanford University Campus. They have retained the same call number, M1835.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the research and writing of anthropologist Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, as well as material from her siblings and husband Jean Comhaire. Her papers include manuscripts with field notes; newpapers (La Voix des Femmes, Le Temps, L’Universitaire Colonial); published and unpublished articles; photographs of Haiti and her trips to Congo, Nigeria, Mali and other unidentified places; old maps of Haiti, the city of Port-au-Prince, the valley of Marbial, Kenscoff; songs and musical scores; phonograph recordings of voodoo ceremonies; personal and work related correspondence before, during and after World War II; and approx 500 photographs taken during Comhaire-Sylvain's research.
Also included is material from Jean Comhaire, Georges Sylvain, Pierre Sylvain, and Madeleine Sylvain-Bouchereau.
Biographical Note
Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain was Haiti’s first black female anthropologist. She studied in Kingston and Port-au-Prince before she obtained her Bachelor’s degree and Doctorate in Paris. Besides her interest in Haitian folklore and social issues of the condition of women in Haiti and Africa, her research focused on the origins of Creole language; an idiom considered juvenile and worthless at that time. She had chosen a difficult path but her quaint work, disregarded by her peers, sparked the interest of famous Polish anthropologist Bronislaw Malinowski. The latter invited her in London where she became her research assistant while studying at London University and later at the London School of Economics. She also conducted successful research at the British Museum that resulted in her major work regarding the African roots of Haitian Creole.
Suzanne traveled the world and conducted field research in Kenscoff and Marbial (Haiti), Kinshasa (Congo), Lomé (Togo) and Nsukka (Nigeria) worked with renowned anthropologists such as Melville Herskovits and Alfred Metraux who entrusted her and her husband Jean Comhaire with a mission of the UNESCO in Haiti. Suzanne has also taught at the New School for Social Research in New York and was appointed member of the United Nations trusteeship council for Togo and Cameroon under French administration.
Suzanne came from a very special family, her uncle Benito Sylvain was one of the founding fathers of the Pan African movement and her father George Sylvain (1866-1925) was an important figure of the resistance against the American occupation in Haiti. Suzanne was the oldest of a family of seven who impacted Haiti in a positive way. Her sister Yvonne Sylvain (1907-1989) was the first female gynecologist and obstetrician of Haiti. Madeleine Sylvain Bouchereau (1905-1970) was one of the founders of the Feminine League for Social Action (Ligue Feminine d’Action Sociale) which fought for women’s legal rights such as education, equality for married women and suffrage) while her brother, the poet Normil Sylvain (1900-1929) was the founder of La Revue Indigène. Finally, her youngest brother Pierre Sylvain (1910-1991) was a botanist who published several reports on coffee production in Ethiopia.
Anthropology.; Nigeria.; Music -- Haiti; Haiti -- Maps; Africa; Tales -- Congo (Democratic Republic); Haiti; Women -- Social conditions.; Congo (Democratic Republic); Comhaire, Jean; Comhaire-Sylvain, Suzanne
- Series 1: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain materials
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains research notes and handwritten notebooks by Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain that she used for research and teaching. Notes include French translations of Haitian Creole folktales, songs and musical notation. There are also French translation of Congolese and Nigerian folktales, collected by Suzanne Comhaire_Sylvain. There are ethnographic notes on the people in Kenscoff, Haiti, nad women and children in Nigeria and Kenya. This series also includes studies on language in Cuba and on the roots of African languages in Haitian Creole.
  - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain notebooks 1937 1959 (1 out of 4) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain notebooks 1937 1959 (2 out of 4) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain notebooks 1937 1959 (3 out of 4) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain notebooks 1937 1959 (4 out of 4) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Creole tales translated in French (1 out of 2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Creole tales translated in French (2 out of 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Songs in creole and musical scores (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Article: La chanson haitienne; Creole songs with musical scores (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - folktales and romances; Mort et funerailles (notes); generalites sur Haiti (notes) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - publications: naissance, mort et etat civil a Kenscoff (Haiti) 1959; l'instruction des filles a Lome 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Contes Leopoldville by Suzanne and Jean Comhaire, August 1943 - December 1945 (1 out of 2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Comhaire, Jean; Comhaire-Sylvain, Suzanne
  - Contes Leopoldville by Suzanne and Jean Comhaire, August 1943 - December 1945 (2 out of 2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - l'espagnol populaire a Cuba, Suzanne Sylvain, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Les femmes de Kinshasa circa 1943 (manuscript with annotations) 1 out of 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Les femmes de Kinshasa circa 1943 (manuscript with annotations) 2 out of 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Short stories and folktales (Haiti circa 1937) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Montagard d'Haiti, Kenscoff (manuscript with notes of the author); correspondence Jean Comhaire and Dominique Desjeux 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Quelques themes communs aux contes zairois reunis ici et aux contes haitiens receuillis par l'auteur (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Essays and notes on Haitian folklore; notes on Cochon-gras (Haiti) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Essays and articles about the African legacy in Haiti an African derived words in Haitian creole by Suzanne and Jean Comhaire (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Articles, statistics, newspaper article about Kenscoff with introduction and notes from the author (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Communication faite au III ieme congres des Caraibes Port-au-Prince, Haiti; Notes on craftmen in the region of Cocon-Gras, Haiti (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Social analysis of Haitian rural society culture, habits, social issues, economy etc. (1 out of 2) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Social analysis of Haitian rural society culture, habits, social issues, economy etc. (2 out of 2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper articles and notes about Kenscoff, Haiti (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Publication about social development women in Kenya; Notes and short stories; correspondence with editors (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Choix de l'emplacement de la colonie agricole by Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain; The significance of Caribbean pluralism by M.G Smith (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - A child, my child, nouvelle nigerienne, by Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain circa 1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Directory of African women, United Nations Economic Comission for Africa by Suzanne and Jean Comhaire (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Speech at the Asemblea extraordinaria de la comision interamericana de mujeres Buenos Aires 1949; Report to the Secretary of state and foreign affairs of Haiti; Correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Montagnard d' Haiti: les paysans de la Region de Kenscoff introduction et notes de Jean Comhaire (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Essay about Haitian oral literature and Haitian folklore; short stories included in the essay (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Suzanne and Jean Comhaire articles circa 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Social and economic study of Saint Marc Haiti; articles and notes on other regions of Haiti (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Masamba et ses amis, contes congolais (manuscript) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript: Vieillir a Port au Prince (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: Paysans de la Region de Kenscoff (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: Paysans de la Region de Kenscoff (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: Folktales and Short Stories from Bantu People with translation in French (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: Folktales and Short Stories from Bantu People with translation in French (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: Masamba et ses amis; Contes Zairois racontes et expliques a Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain, Kinshasa circa 1943 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: Masamba et ses amis; Contes Congolais (1of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: Masamba et ses amis; Contes Congolais (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: Riddles and "Romances" Creole, translated in French (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: Folktales from Marbial (Haiti) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: Folktales in Creole, translated in French (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: Notes about the Society of Kenscoff (Haiti); Article: L'Enregistrement des Naissances et Deces comme Source d'Information Ethnographique a Kenscoff; Short stories, songs (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: Social study of Kenscoff (Haiti); Folktales by Florent Marin (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript: Paysans de la Region de Kenscoff, Haiti (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: "Mariage" (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: Folktales from Bantu People, translated in French circa 1945 (1 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: Folktales from Bantu People, translated in French circa 1945 (2 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: Folktales from Bantu People, translated in French circa 1945 (3 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: Folktales from Bantu People, translated in French circa 1945 (4 of 4) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: Folktales and short stories from Marbial (Haiti), notes, analysis and comments of the author (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: Folktales and short stories from Marbial (Haiti), notes, analysis and comments of the author (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: Riddles and proverbs in Haitian Creole; Translations and notes of the author; Speech: la femme et la societe; Notes: Port Prince Revisite: sous developpement et evolution (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: Folktales and short stories in Haitian Creole, translated in French (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publications 1933-1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publications 1947-1996 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publications 1938-1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publication 1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publication 1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publications 1951-1982 (1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publications 1951-1982 (2 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire-Sylvain Publications 1951-1982 (3 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: From: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain To: Dr. Helen Walker, Professor of Education, Columbia University (From 1944-1946) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Between Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain and Archibald MacLeish (September 1943-March 1944); Between Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain and Thomas A. Sebeok (November 1943-February 1944) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Between Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain and Henry Allen Moe (Guggenheim Foundation), September-May 1943 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: From: Jean Comhaire To: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain; From: Denise Paulme Scheefffner to Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain; From: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain To: Jean Comhaire; From: Dominique Aguessy To: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain; From: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain To: Dominique Aguessy (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Between Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain and Edwin W. Smith (International African Institute) (August-November 1945) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: with editors: Suzanne and Jean Comhaire (1943-1969) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: From: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain To: Dr. A. Burssens (professor) (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: From: Alfred Metraux To: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain (1948) (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Tableau des Cours par Ecole Libre des Hautes Etudes January 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Magazine clippings on Yvonne Sylvain (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 2: Jean Comhaire, Georges Sylvain, Pierre Sylvain, and Madeleine Sylvain-Bouchereau materials
  This series includes manuscripts, correspondence, news and publications, by and about Suzanne's husband and by her immediate family members.
  - Scrapbook, personnal belonging Sylvain family and Jean Comhaire (copies) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Book reviews and bibliography (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - articles on economic changes and haitian family (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook personnal belongings Sylvain family and Jean Comhaire (original) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook personnal belongings Sylvain family and Jean Comhaire (copies) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Madeleine and Yvonne Sylvain Newspapers extracts (original and copies) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1942 to 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tableau des cours: Ecole Libre des Hautes Etudes, January 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - magazine clippings on Yvonne Sylvain (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Madeleine Sylvain Bouchereau: photoraphs, letter and nespaper clippings. January 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Notes about women in Africa circa 1982 by Jean Comhaire (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Folktales and Nationhood in Haiti by Jean Comhaire (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Egyetemi evfolyamtarsam Emlekere by Prof Galdi Laszlo Kedves regi; Notes du 6 Juin 1982 by Jean Comhaire; La Femme Africaine Face a la Vie Moderne by Jean Comhaire (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, Interviews, and Reminiscences by Jean Comhaire circa 1982-1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: From: Dr. Marcel Berard To: President Paul Eugene Magloire (1954); From: Henri Deschamps To: Jean Comhaire (1943); From: Unknown To: Pere Hochegger (1984); From: Jean Comhaire To: Jacques Chevalier (1966); From: A.A. Diop To: Suzanne C. Sylvain (1969) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: From: Suzanne Comhaire-Sylvain To: Jean Comhaire, Buenos Aires, Argentina (August 4, 1949-August 23, 1949); From: Guy S. Metraux To: Jean Comhaire, Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico (August 4, 1949) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Sylvain Family (January-October 1945) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Sylvain Family (January-December 1944) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Sylvain Family (1948-1971) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Sylvain Family (May-October 1946) (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Sylvain Family (August-December 1943) (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Sylvain Family (dates missing) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: From: Jean Comhaire To: Reverend Hochegger (1984); From: Jean Comhaire To: Steyler Verlag (1984); From: Reverend Hochegger To: Jean Comhaire (1984); From: Dominique Desjeux To: Jean Comhaire (1981) (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Publications: Pierre Sylvain Publications and Miscellaneous Documents, 1930-1972 (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Pierre Sylvain Publications and Miscellaneous Documents, 1930-1972 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Madeleine G. Sylvain Boucherau Publications 1944-1954 (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Madeleine G. Sylvain Boucherau Publications 1944-1954 (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Jeanne G. Sylvain Publication 1949 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Publications: Cric? Crac! Fables de la Fontaine Racontees par un Montagnard Haitien et Transcrites en Vers Creole by Georges Sylvain (1901) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Portrait of Georges Sylvain and Biography of Georges Sylvain (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Publications: Yvonne G. Sylvain publication titled "Conseiller en Hygiene de la Maternite et de l'Enfance." Mai 1961-Avril 1967 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Newspapers and clippings
  This series includes newspaper clippings and short runs of newspapers mainly from Haitian news sources. There is a short run of women's suffrage newspapers, "La voix des femmes", issues for 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1943, 1947, for which Madeleine Sylvain Bouchereau (1905-1970), Suzanne's sister was a contributor. Dates of all newspapers range from 1936-1959.
  - Haiti Sun: August 5, 1956; September 8, 1957 (Flat-box 18, Folder 1)
  - La Lanterne: November 13, 20 1937 (Flat-box 18, Folder 2)
  - La Francaise: October 10, 17 1936 (Flat-box 18, Folder 3)
  - Le Justier: August 22, September 7, and September 19, 1949 (Flat-box 18, Folder 4)
  - Clipping "Le Charme D'Haiti" by Suzanne Sylvain, Haiti Sun: February 24, 1957, September 8, 1957, May 3, 1959, August 26, 1956, March 31, 1957. (Flat-box 18, Folder 5)
  - La Croisade: July 3, 1937 (Flat-box 18, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Defender: Foreign New Page October3, 1936; The Chicago Defender: October 2, 1937; Le Matin: May 5, 1941; Lloyd Annversois: September 2, 1956; Haiti Miroir: October 14, 1956: The Tanganyira Standard: February 6, 1957; Haiti Journal: August 27, 1957 (Flat-box 18, Folder 7)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: February-March 1937, April 1937, February-March 1938, March 1939, October-November 1940, December 1943 (Flat-box 20, Folder 1)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: January 11 and 25, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 2)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: February 8, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 3)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: February 22, March 8, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 4)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: March 22, April 12, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 5)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: April 26, May 10, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 6)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: June 28, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 7)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: July 12, August 9, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 8)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: August 9, and 23, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 9)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: September 6 and 10, 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 10)
  - La Voix Des Femmes: October 4 and 18, November 22 1947 (Flat-box 20, Folder 11)
  - Le Temps: 17 June 1936 (Flat-box 21, Folder 1)
  - Le Temps: 20 June 1936 (Flat-box 21, Folder 2)
  - Le Temps: 19 June 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 3)
  - Le Temps: 23 June 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 4)
  - Le Temps: 3 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 5)
  - Le Temps: 7 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 6)
  - Le Temps: 9 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 7)
  - Le Temps: 10 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 8)
  - Le Temps: 14 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 9)
  - Le Temps: 18 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 10)
  - Le Temps: 21 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 11)
  - Le Temps: 26 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 12)
  - Le Temps: 31 July 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 13)
  - Le Temps: 4 August 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 14)
  - Le Temps: 11 August 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 15)
  - Le Temps: 18 August 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 16)
  - Le Temps: 21 August 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 17)
  - Le Temps: 25 August 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 18)
  - Le Temps: 28 August 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 19)
  - Le Temps: 1 September 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 20)
  - Le Temps: 4 September 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 21)
  - Le Temps: 8 September 1937 (Flat-box 21, Folder 22)
  - Le Temps: 23 February 1938 (Flat-box 21, Folder 23)
  - Le Temps: 27 February 1938 (Flat-box 21, Folder 24)
  - Le Temps: 21 September 1938 (Flat-box 21, Folder 25)
  - Le Temps: 28 September 1938 (Flat-box 21, Folder 26)
  - Le Temps: 7 September 1940 (Flat-box 21, Folder 27)
  - Le Temps: 26 October 1940 (Flat-box 21, Folder 28)
  - A Propos de Shada: April 1944 (Flat-box 21, Folder 29)
  - L'Univeritaire Colonial (Flat-box 21, Folder 30)
- Series 4: Photographs and audio recordings
  This is a large collection of photographs that were taken as part of Suzanne's anthropological research in Haiti, Nigeria, and the Democratic Republic of the Congo. There are some family photos as well. The collection includes some negative, some of which are not printed in the collection. The glass recordings of the music have been transferred to the Archives of Recorded Sound, located in the Music Buildingon the Stanford University Campus. They have retained the same call number, M1835.
  - Photographs: Haiti circa 1943 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Haiti circa 1957 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Haiti, Yvonne Sylvain (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Congo, circa 1940's (Box 16, Folders 4-5)
  - Photographs: Nigeria circa 1945-1950 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Photographs Nigeria, Leopoldville (DRC), and Haiti, circa 1940's (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - photographs: Sylvain family (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Madeleine Sylvain-Bouchereau, Venezuela 1948 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Nigeria, Leopolville (DRC) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Leopoldville (DRC) circa 1943 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Negatives 1 out of 4 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Negatives 2 out of 4 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Negatives 3 out of 4 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Negatives 4 out of 4 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Seven glass-based instantaneous disc recordings
    Existence and Location of Originals
    Box containing the phonograph recordings has been transferred to the Archive of Recorded Sound, located in the Music Building at Stanford (https://library.stanford.edu/ars). They have retained the same call number, M1835.
  - photocopies of record sleeves stored in the Archive of Recorded Sound (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Series 5: Maps
  This series includes older maps of Haiti. There are hand-drawn maps of Kenscoff, Haiti. There are detailed maps of Port-au-Prince and topographic maps of Haiti.
  - Plan de la ville de Port-au-Prince en 1860 (Elie Dubois,draftsman V.Zankevitch) (Flat-box 19, Item 1)
  - Carte-guide et plan de Port-au-prince (George Séjour, architecte) (Flat-box 19, Item 2)
  - Panoramic and monumental maps of Port-au-prince, Cap-Haitien and Pétionville (By Pierre Durocher and Joseph.J. Charles) (Flat-box 19, Item 3)
  - Republica de Haiti esquema de la distribucion de los principales (Servicio tecnico de Mineria y Geologia. Estados Unidos de Venezuela, Ministerio de Fomento. Dfraftsman E.J.P.H) (Flat-box 19, Item 4)
  - Kenscoff, Marbial, Fond Ferrier (Service technique de l'imprimerie Henri Deschamps) (Flat-box 19, Item 5)
  - Carte de la Republique d'Haiti (Service technique de l'imprimerie Henri Deschamps) (Flat-box 19, Item 6)
  - Marigot, Haiti, Département de l'ouest arrondissement Jacmel (U.S army map service, corps of engineers, department of the Army, Washington DC) (Flat-box 19, Item 7)
  - Port-au-Prince, Hati, Département de l'ouest arrondissement Port-au-Prince (U.S army map service, corps of engineers, department of the Army, Washington DC) (Flat-box 19, Item 8)
  - Fond Ferrier, Haiti, Département de l'ouest (U.S army map service, corps of engineers, department of the Army, Washington DC) (Flat-box 19, Item 9)
  - Mornes au sud de Port-au-Prince: Pétionville, Kenscoff, Marbial, Fond Ferrier (Suzanne et Jean Comhaire ) (Flat-box 19, Item 10)
  - Ville de Cayes, République d' Haiti (ingenieurs du service de Geodetic et de cartographie, et l'Armée d'Haiti) (Flat-box 19, Item 11)
  - Carte géologique de la republique d' Haiti (Par Jacques Butterlin ) (Flat-box 19, Item 12)
  - Esquema de la distribucion de las muestras de calizas y arcillas en Petionville y alrededores (Servicio tecnico de Mineria y Geologia. Estados Unidos de Venezuela, Ministerio de Fomento. G Gonzales B.) (Flat-box 19, Item 13)